Mohammed Moataz

Giza, Egypt +20 100 858 1523

Gmail:

imohammedmoataz@gmail.com LinkedIn: mohammed-moataz Github: MohammedMoataz

Website:

mohammed-moataz.vercel.app

SUMMARY

Resourceful **software engineer** with both front-end and back-end development experience. Smart and consistently educated designer of user interactions on sound and user-friendly websites and databases. Proven troubleshooting with a solid grounding in data-driven concepts and applications.

EXPERIENCE

Catch Code, Giza — Software Engineer

Jun 2023 - Oct 2023

- Augmented with the backend team to develop APIs using Node.JS
- Collaborated to develop the desktop application using JavaFX.
- Analyzed, prioritized, and problem-solved several tasks concurrently with minimum supervision.

CBMIS, Remotely— Software Engineer Trainee

Jun 2022 - Jan 2023

- Learned new emerging technologies.
- Analyzed, prioritized, and problem-solved several tasks.

EDUCATION

Faculty of Computers and Artificial Intelligence Helwan University, Cairo — Very Good

September 2019 - July 2023.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Concepts

OOP / Data Structures / Design Patterns / Restful APIs / GraphQL

Development

BlockChain / Java Spring / Node.JS / React.JS

SKILLS

Adaptability.

Teammates' Motivation

Problem-Solving.

Fast learning.

Teamwork.

Good Listener.

CERTIFICATIONS

Google IT Support, Google

Dec 2022

Agile Scrum, ODC

Sep 2022

ITI Java Spring Developer, ITI

Sep 2022

Web Design, NTI

Aug 2022

Google Project Management Specialization, Google

Tun 2022

Jun 2022

LANGUAGES

Arabic

English

Database

MySQL / MongoDB / Firestore

Tools

Docker / Git / Jira / Trello

VOLUNTEERING

Google Developers Student Club - Helwan University

2022 Technical Head.

- Flutter Instructor.
- Responsible for How-To workshops. 2021 Technical Core Team Member.

Data Structures Instructor.

Online - Helwan University

2022 Vice president.

2019 Media team member.